fontba.se 2018-09-07

# FontBase — Terms of Service

## Instead of “General Words”

This Privacy Policy describes how we collect personal information, use and store it and choices You have regarding the information. Herewith we use the following terms, where this Privacy Policy applies: the website [https://fontba.se](https://fontba.se/), all its content and links ( **“Website”** ) as well as FontBase desktop App ( **“App”** ). Use of the Websites includes accessing, browsing, or registering within the App, including but not limited to blogs, support correspondence, product and services information (all together, including using the App and communication with the FontBase referred to as **“Services”** ).

 **“FontBase”** , **“We”** , **“our”** and **“us”** refers to the FontBase entity: **“Dominik Levitsky Studio”**.

Please, read this Privacy Policy carefully. If You do not agree with the terms, please do not access or use the Services. Users can access, print, download and save these Privacy Policy at any time. The Privacy Policy will be permanently accessible on the Website. By providing any of the information about Yourself, as well as using of the Services You confirm that You accept this Privacy Policy and that You agree to comply with it. If You do not agree to this Privacy Policy, You must not use the Services.

In case You have any questions relating to the conditions contained in this Privacy Policy, You can contact us by email to [mail@fontba.se](mailto:mail@fontba.se). Or at any of our social media pages: [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/FontBaseApp), [Twitter](https://twitter.com/FontBaseApp). Or via mail to the address: _“Dominik Levitsky Studio”, Pionierska 19 Wroclaw, Dolnoslaskie 53-212 Poland_.

Do not hesitate to contact us at any time with any queries. **We are here to help!**

## Our Statement

The protection of information, that You have provided to us is of our top priority so we will maintain administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. Those safeguards will include measures for preventing unauthorized access, use, modification, deletion and disclosure of information by our personnel or third parties. Before sharing received data with any of our third party service providers, we will ensure that the third party maintains, at a minimum, reasonable data practices for maintaining the confidentiality and security of data and preventing unauthorized access.

## What We do Collect and When

We collect different information about You when You use the App and Website. For convenience, we have divided it into two small groups: **automatic collection** and **vulnerable**. Automatic collection: whenever You access or use the Services, we may use technologies that automatically or passively collect information about how the Services are accessed and used. Vulnerable collection: includes the information, You provide us upon Your own will to do so. Herewith You can see what we do collect when You use:

##  **1\. The app**

## (a) Automatic Collection. (“Other Data”)

We automatically collect **Your IP address** , Your computer’s **unique ID** , **operating system** , the **version of application** , downloaded on Your computer; **time when You open and close** the App; **the errors** , which may occur during Your use of the App and the fonts downloaded to the App. We may use this information to, among other things, help diagnose problems with our servers, analyze trends, resolve bugs and gather information for aggregate use. We do collect it every time, when You use the Services. We see how much time You spend using Services and when just to adjust our App and make it as user friendly as possible. 

As with most websites and technology services delivered over the Internet, our servers automatically collect information when You access or use the App and record it in log files on Your computer. This log data include App version, when the App was launched, when was closed, Your actions in the App, crash reports and operation system, technical messages. This is needed to support the normal functioning of the App on Your computer with minimum service errors.

## (b) Vulnerable Collection (“Personal Data”)

 **FontBase does not ask You to provide us with any information before You become Awesome.** We simply do not need it and You are not bothered filling the forms. When this moment occurs and You are purchasing Awesome, we need the information about You for billing purposes. That is the moment when we are collecting the information about You. Our form contains the minimum information required for successful processing of a credit card transaction and register the user to receive technical support: **Billing address** , **Full Name** , **Country** , **Email** , **Credit Card details**. Nothing more than this. All information including credit card numbers are always collected via a secure server to prevent unauthorized access during transmission of the data. Do not buy from the other resources, our official Website is only this one: [https://fontba.se](https://fontba.se/). 

## **2\. The website**

## (a) Automatic Collection. (“Other Data”)

We personally do not collect the information, when You simply searching through our Website. All we do on this stage — we are plugging [Google Analitics](https://analytics.google.com/) to receive the analytics for our legitimate interest and analyzing how to promote our Services. The information we receive is in aggregated way so we cannot identify the person.

## (b) Vulnerable Collection (“Personal Data”)

Also, if You want to receive notifications, other awesome messages from us, You can provide us with Your email and we will also collect it.

“Other Data” and “Personal Data” altogether referred to as the “Data” (Including the processing of any messages, files or other content submitted through Services accounts), to the extent information is associated with an identified or identifiable natural person and is protected as personal data under applicable data protection law.

## What We don’t Collect and Why

Don’t worry, we can’t read data off Your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites :). We actually do not use cookies by ourselves.

FontBase do not need the information, that it cannot use in ways that are not compatible with the purposes for which it was collected or subsequently authorized by the User. FontBase will take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information is relevant to its intended use, accurate, complete and current and use industry-standard specifications for storing and processing. We will not sell Your e-mail address, nor do we provide it to advertisers or mass marketers. In other words, You will never receive junk mail based on information You submit directly to FontBase.

## How We Process and Where We Store

Actually, we don't! Really now, we are being Data Controller in terms of GDPR are not storing any User Data on our servers. All the Data is processed by our third party Processors, who are the **Data Processors** (the current are mentioned below) to provide infrastructure Services, and to help us provide customer support and email notifications as follows:

  *  **Chargebee** chargebee.com — Handling and storing all subscription data
  *  **Auth0** auth0.com — Handling and storing all the login process and authentication data
  *  **MongoDB Atlas** mongodb.com — Handling and storing all the IP, unique user ID, OS, FontBase App version, log data (time of opening/closing the App, errors), fonts added to the App

We also store log files on Your computer, as we already mentioned it above. In case You forgot, this is the information, regarding: when the app was launched, when it was closed, crash reports, Your actions in app, service messages — these are stored on Your computer.

Feel free to read more about above services if You don't trust us or just curious and like reading documents. Prior to engaging of these third party Processors, FontBase performed due diligence to evaluate their privacy, security and confidentiality practices. Data we collect may be transferred to, stored and processed in any other country in which we or our Processors maintain facilities. Upon the start of enforcement of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), we will continue to ensure that transfers of Personal Information to a third country or an international organization are subject to appropriate safeguards.

We process Personal Information on the following legal bases: (1) with Your consent; (2) as necessary to provide Services; and (3) as necessary for our legitimate interests in providing the Services where those interests do not override Your fundamental rights and freedom related to data privacy.

Given the nature of communications and information processing technology, FontBase cannot guarantee that Data, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our systems or otherwise in our care, will be absolutely safe from intrusion by others.

## Why We Collect

We collect Data for the list of following reasons:

  *  **(a)** to provide, update, maintain and protect our Services. This includes supporting, delivery of the Services, prevent or address service errors, security or technical issues, analyze and monitor trends;
  *  **(b)** As required by applicable law, legal process or regulation;
  *  **(c)** To send emails and make other communications. To communicate with You by responding to Your requests, comments and questions. If You contact Us, we may use Your Other Information to respond. We may send You service, technical and other administrative emails, messages and other types of communications and to respond to any questions and requests You may have. We may also contact You to inform about changes in our Services and important Services-related notices, such as security and fraud notices. These communications are considered part of the Services and You may not opt out of them. In addition, we may sometimes send emails about new Awesome features, promotions or other news about FontBase. These are marketing messages so You can control whether You want to receive them;
  *  **(d)** To process transactions and track purchase history and verify Your identity for Awesome subscription. FontBase may need to contact You for invoicing, account management and similar reasons and we use account data to keep track of billing and payments according to Your Awesome subscription;
  *  **(e)** For developing and Service fixing. FontBase tries to make the Services as useful as possible, so we are using the information to develop the Service and fix the bugs and errors as well as to come up with new Awesome features;
  *  **(f)** For any purposes which may have been disclosed to You at the time You provided Your Personal Information to us;
  *  **(g)** To detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies, be fraudulent, or be illegal.

FontBase do not need the information, that it cannot use in ways that are not compatible with the purposes for which it was collected or subsequently authorized by the User. FontBase will take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information is relevant to its intended use, accurate, complete and current and use industry-standard specifications for storing and processing. We will not sell Your e-mail address, nor do we provide it to advertisers or mass marketers. In other words, You will never receive junk mail based on information You submit directly to FontBase.

## Changes to Data/deletion of Data

You control the Personal Data that You provide to us in connection with the Services; however certain fields may be required for the provision of Services. We endeavor to retain Your Personal Data for as long as Your Awesome is active or as needed to provide You with certain Services for purchasing Awesome. We will also retain and use Your Personal Data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

You have:

  *  **(a)** The right to have Your Personal Data erased from our Services if it is no longer necessary for the purpose for which it was collected, You withdraw consent and no other legal basis for processing exists, or You believe Your fundamental rights to data privacy and protection outweigh our legitimate interest in continuing the processing. The deletion of Personal Data may result in changes of using Services. We may retain Personal Data pertaining to You for as long as necessary for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. This may include keeping Your Personal Data after You have deactivated Your account for the period of time needed for FontBase to pursue legitimate business interests, conduct audits, comply with legal obligations, unless applicable law prevents it from returning or destroying all or part of Data;
  *  **(b)** The right to request the FontBase to provide You with the information we maintain about You. We promise to do our best and to process with the request during seven (7) business days;
  *  **(c)** FontBase offers users the ability to correct or change the information collected during registration. Users may change this information at any time and as often as necessary;
  *  **(d)** The right to be removed from all special promotions, software product or service updates and upgrades, and new product or service announcements.

Within forty eight hours (48) from request of deletion of information, FontBase deletes all information it posses about You. For any of the above, please contact us at: [mail@fontba.se](mailto:mail@fontba.se).

## Age Limitations

To the extent prohibited by applicable law, FontBase does not allow use of our Services by anyone younger than it is stated by applicable law. If You learn that anyone younger than applicable legal age to him has unlawfully provided us with personal data, please contact us and we will take steps to delete such information.

## Changes to this Policy

As the laws and standards evolve, as well as our business, we may, at our sole discretion, revise this Privacy Policy and periodically update this document with the changes. We encourage You to review our Privacy Policy to stay informed. If we make changes that materially alter Your privacy rights, we will provide additional notice via email or through the Services. If You disagree with the changes to this Privacy Policy, You should stop using the Services and deactivate Your Awesome account and let us know so we will remove all Your Personal Data.

## How We Protect Your Information

We take reasonable and appropriate measures to protect the Data we collect through the Services, including the implementation and maintenance of organizational, technical and administrative procedures to prevent unauthorized or unlawful access, disclosure or destruction. Users of the Services must also do their part in protecting the data, systems, networks and service they are utilizing. Please always be sure You are not disclosing Your password and login details for Your Awesome account to someone else. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Data, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you use the Services and provide us with your information at your own risk. If by any chance you have reason to believe that your Personal Data is no longer secure (for example, Your Awesome login and password may have been compromised), please immediately write to us at [mail@fontba.se](mailto:mail@fontba.se).

## Right to Lodge a Complaint

We take reasonable and appropriate measures to protect the Data we collect through the Services, including the implementation and maintenance of organizational, technical and administrative procedures to prevent unauthorized or unlawful access, disclosure or destruction. Users of the Services must also do their part in protecting the data, systems, networks and service they are utilizing. Please always be sure You are not disclosing Your password and login details for Your Awesome account to someone else. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Data, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you use the Services and provide us with your information at your own risk. If by any chance you have reason to believe that your Personal Data is no longer secure (for example, Your Awesome login and password may have been compromised), please immediately write to us at [mail@fontba.se](mailto:mail@fontba.se).

The Inspector General for the Protection of Personal Data (hereinafter referred to as the "Inspector General"). Polish: Generalny Inspektor Ochrony Danych Osobowych)

Contact information: _Office of the Inspector General for the Protection of Personal Data Biuro Generalnego Inspektora Ochrony Danych Osobowych Stawki 2, 00-193 Warsaw, Poland, T (22) 531 03 00 F (22) 531 03 01. kancelaria@giodo.gov.pl The Office of the Inspector General is open from Monday to Friday from 8 am to 4 pm._
